大家好
hey everybody
欢迎来到这个讲座
welcome to this talk
关于使用V编写Elm应用程序
about writing Elm applications using v
今天我们将探讨L编程语言
today we're going to explore the l programming language
一种功能性的
a functional
一种用于构建网络应用程序的函数式编程语言
programming language for building web applications
以及如何将其整合到我们的VT构建工具中。
and how we can integrate it into our VT build tool
我的名字叫Lindsay Ordell
my name is Lindsay ordell
我是no red公司的一名软件工程师
I am a software engineer at no red Inc
no red Inc正在开发
no red Inc is developing
为英语教师开发工具，用于教授
tools for English teachers to teach
初中和高中学生
middle and high schoolers
英语和写作
English and writing
我们还可以使用
we also get to use
非常酷的编程语言，如
really cool programming languages such as
Elm和Haskell
Elm and Haskell
如果你喜欢这些很酷的编程语言
if you like these cool programming languages
或者你喜欢教育
or you like education
请考虑在noaretink com上申请工作。
please consider applying at noaretink com jobs
我也是vete Elm模板的维护者
I am also the maintainer of the vete Elm template
的模板，该模板
template that
融合了Elm在vet
incorporates Elm in vet
和很多工具
and a lot of the tools that
我们今天要讨论的是
we're going to be talking about today
我们不是在探讨模板本身
we're not exploring the template itself
所以，请在Github的Lindsay k word l slash上查看
so please check it out at Lindsay k word l slash
github上的vet Elm模板
vet Elm template on github
首先
first off
让我们深入了解一下
let's just dive in
什么是Elm
what is Elm
Elm本身是一种函数式编程语言
Elm itself is a functional programming language
函数式编程在javascript生态系统中非常
functional programming is very
现在在javascript生态系统中被引用
invoke right now in the javascript ecosystem
但是
but
Elm是作为一种功能性编程语言设计的
Elm is designed as a functional programming language
与javascript不同，它是非常面向对象的
unlike javascript which is very object oriented
或命令式的
or imperative
它也只有纯函数
it also only has pure functions
所以，如果你想到了javascript
so if you're thinking of javascript
而你调用一个函数
and you call a function
你可以产生副作用，你可以做其他的调用
you can make side effects you can do other calls
你可以，如果你在注释和环境中
you can if you're in the note and environment
你可以进行恶意的调用，你可以做坏事
you can make malicious calls you can do bad things
Elm不允许这样做
Elm doesn't allow that
Elm只有纯函数
Elm only has pure functions
所以只有提供给函数的输入才是
so only the inputs provided to the function are the
可用的值
values available
而唯一的
and the only
输出是函数本身的输出
outputs are the output of the function itself
Elm还可以编译成javascript
Elm also compiles to javascript
所以当你在写
so when you are writing
Elm代码并将其编译到网络上时
Elm code and you compile it for the web
你就在运行一个javascript文件
you are running a javascript file
这使得它非常容易被纳入
this makes it really easy to incorporate
到你现有的应用程序和
into your existing applications and
构建环境
build environments
Elm也是静态类型的
Elm is also statically typed
它有一个强大的静态类型系统
it has a strong static type system
这是一个非常强大的系统
this is extremely powerful
如果你使用过类型脚本，你就会对它有一种感觉。
if you've used type script you've had a feel for it
但Elm将它提升到了一个新的水平，即
but Elm takes it to the next level where
所有东西都是强类型的
everything is strongly typed
你所有的函数都被期望返回
all of your functions are expected to return
某些值
certain values
而且由于这种强类型化
and because of that strong typing
你会得到很多帮助
you get a lot of assistance
从Elm编译器本身
from the Elm compiler itself
我们将在一秒钟内讨论这个问题。
which we'll get to in just one second
Elm也支持可变数据，这是一个内置的概念。
Elm also supports a mutable data as a built in concept
Elm不允许突变
Elm doesn't allow mutation
没有任何对象可以让你
there aren't any objects that you can then
操作和修改的对象
manipulate and modify
你只能拥有你所期望的数据
you're just going to have the data that you expect
正如我提到的
and as I mentioned
Elm中有一些有用的错误信息
there are helpful error messages in Elm
所以当你在你的代码库中工作时
so when you are working on your code base
如果你改变了一个类型
if you change a type
或者你在代码的某一部分开始重构时
or if you start refactoring in one part of your code
其他部分就会不同步了
the rest of it will not be in sync
编译器会知道这一点并告诉你
and the compiler will know that and tell you
发生了什么事
what's going on
什么是最好的方法来帮助
what's the best way to help
应对所有这些变化的最佳方法，还有
work through all of those changes and also
这是个有趣的问题
this is a fun one
不存在空
there is no null
没有未定义
there is no undefined
你永远不会在你的运行时中出现未定义无法找到的情况
you will never have undefined cannot be found
在你的运行时中
in your in your runtime
事实上，在运行时也没有例外。
and in fact there are no runtime exceptions
在大多数情况下
for the most part
如果一个Elm应用程序编译成功，它就能正常工作
if an Elm application compiles it works
当你写完你的Elm代码
and when you write your Elm code
并将其部署到网络上时
and you deploy it to the web
你可以肯定的是
you can be sure that
它可能不会做所有
it may not be doing everything
的业务逻辑，但它不会崩溃。
by the business logic that you want it to do
但它不会崩溃
but it will not crash
当你的用户使用它时
when your users are using it
所以，让我们做一个简单的比较
so let's just do a quick comparison
让我们在javascript和Elm生态系统之间做一个快速的比较
between the javascript and Elm ecosystems
在javascript中，如果你想
in javascript if you wanted to
启动一个应用程序并安装一些软件包
start an application and install some packages
你可能会去找npm或者yarn或者pmpm
you probably reach for npm or yarn or pmpm
而在Elm中，这些都是内置的
and in Elm this is all built in
你只需运行Elm install，就可以安装一些东西。
you just run Elm install and you install something
如果你想构建
if you want to build
你运行Elm make，它就会建立一些东西
you run Elm make and it built something
这是很巧妙的
it's pretty neat
在javascript中，如果你想建立一个web应用程序
in javascript if you want to build a web application
你就会去找 react 或 angular 或 view
you're going to reach for react or angular or view
或spelt
or spelt
或固体或任何你喜欢的框架
or solid or whichever framework is your preference
而在Elm中，这些都是内置的
and in Elm this is all built in
我们遵循Elm的架构，这是
we follow the Elm architecture which is
语言的核心基础部分
stacore foundational piece of the language
构建网络应用的基础语言。
for building web applications
在javascript中，如果你想要全局状态管理
in javascript if you want global state management
你需要类似redux和grx pinya的东西
you need something like redux and grx pinya
不管你喜欢哪种全局管理方式
whatever your preferred flavor of global management is
而在Elm中，这也是内置的
and in Elm again this is built in
它是语言架构的一部分
it's part of the architecture of the language
你所有的状态都在全局层面
all of your state lives at the global level
然后被传递到函数中
and then gets passed into functions
记住，这些函数中没有一个
remember that none of those functions
都不能调用这些数据
can call that data
除非它被传入
except if it's passed in
作为一个参数传给函数
as an argument to the function
在javascript中
in javascript
如果你想让它具有不变性
if you want to mill it immutability
你需要联系1
you need to reach out for 1/3 party library
null
or use something like object dot
freeze which is not 100%
null
there are some proposals on the way
for records and lists that are immutable
null
but they're not here yet
in Elm however they are all built in
null
this is the default
and the only way that you can work
null
with data in the Elm language
in javascript
null
if you want types you need another 3rd party tool
type script but in Elm as we discuss
null
static strong type systems are built into the language
in javascript
null
looking at some tools outside of the programming itself
if you want to lint your application you have yes lint
null
and in Elm there is Elm review
a similar tool that allows you to configure in Elm
null
how your code should be linted
in javascript
null
you have access to prettier
so that you can style your code
null
this can also lead to a lot of debates within your team
should we put the dangling comment at the end
null
should we use a single quote or a double quote
as the default
null
what about semicolons
in Elm there is Elm format
null
Elm format formats your code for you
there is no configuration
null
it follows this standard
provided
null
on the Elm website for how code should be formatted
而在javascript中，如果你想做单元测试
and in javascript if you want to do unit testing
你就会去找moka v test
you're going to reach for just moka v test
有很多库你可以使用
there's a number of libraries that you could use
但在Elm中，有Elm test
but in Elm there is Elm test
Elm test允许你在Elm中为Elm编写测试
Elm test allows you to write tests in Elm for Elm
并运行它们
and run them
用一个简单的cli工具运行它们
with a simple cli tool
关于Elm的其他一些好处
some of the other niceties about Elm
的一些其他优点是
are the helpful
编译器给你的错误信息
error messages that the compiler gives you
例如，如果有一个不正确的参数类型
so for example if there is an incorrect argument type
比方说，我们从int调用字符串dot
let's say we're calling string dot from int
调用字符串dot，但传给它的却是一个字符串
but passing it a string
编译器会告诉我们，那是一个字符串
the compiler will tell us that that is a string
但是from int需要第一个参数是一个int
but from int needs the first argument to be an int
如果你想把一个字符串转换成一个int
if you want to convert a string into an int
你就把字符串dot转换成int
you string dot to int
所以Elm在这方面很有帮助
so Elm is very helpful in this way
为我们提供提示和指导
providing us hints and guides
提供了提示和指导，告诉我们代码中的
as to what the code
或你的实际意思。
is expecting or what you might have actually meant
另一种情况是无效的情况
another case is the invalid case
如果你有一个if语句
if you have an if statement
而你在一个函数中返回一个值
and you're returning a value in a function
那是唯一的
that's the only
的那种值可以从一个函数中返回
kind of value that can be returned from a function
所以，如果我们的if语句的开头返回一个字符串
so if the start of our if statement returns a string
而中间返回一个字符串
and the middle returns a string
而第三个值返回一个数字
and the 3rd value returns a number
这是不有效的
that's not valid
第三个分支是一个数字类型的数字
the 3rd branche is a number of type number
但之前的所有分支的结果都是字符串
but all the previous branches result in string
然后它告诉我们，在一个if中的所有分支
and then it tells us that all branches in an if
的所有分支必须产生相同类型的值
must produce the same type of values
然后给了我们
and then gives us
指南，说明我们如何编写
guides on how we can write
自定义类型，可以将
custom types that can incorporate
不同类型的数据
different types of data
如果我们真的需要这样做的话
if we really need to do that
我们今天的第三个例子是真实性。
the 3rd example that we have today is truthiness
在javascript中，我们有 "真实性 "这个概念
in javascript we have this concept of truthiness
如果你想知道
if you want to know
的话
that
一个列表有数据
a list has data
你通常可以直接调用
you can typically just call like
我在这里演示的是字符串长度
I'm demoing here string length
然后再调用一个字符串
and then a string
如果结果是0以外的任何数字
if that comes out to any number but 0
那么我们就知道这个字符串是存在的
then we know that the string is present
那里有数据
there is data there
在javascript中是这样的，但在Elm中不是这样的
in javascript but in Elm that's not how it works
在Elm中，如果你想做这样的比较
in Elm if you want to make this kind of comparison
你需要实际
you need to actually
确定字符串的长度大于0
determine that the string length is greater than 0
因为Elm不具有真理性
because Elm does not have truthiness
正如我们在提示中看到的那样
as we can see in the hint
榆树不具备真实性
Elm does not have truthiness
这样，即时字符串和
such that instant strings and
列表会自动转换为十亿级
lists are automatically converted to billions
而Elm则明确地进行这种转换
do that conversion explicitly
所以Elm再次
so again Elm
编译器实际上是在指导我们
compiler is actually guiding us
通过学习如何在Elm中工作的过程
through the process of learning how to work in Elm
这是一些Elm代码的例子
and this is an example of some Elm code
这是很基本的
it's very basic
我们在这里所做的就是在屏幕上添加一个
all we're doing here is adding a
计数器到屏幕上
counter to the screen
有一个加号按钮和一个减号按钮
with a plus button and a minus button
这样我们就可以对数字进行递增和递减了
so that we can increment and decrement in numbers
这就是
that is
随着数字的变化在屏幕上重新显示出来
re rendered on the screen as the number changes
所以让我们快速浏览一下这个文件
so let's just walk through this file real quick
在顶部有一个模块main，暴露了所有的东西
at the top there is module main exposing everything
所以点点代表一切
so the dot dot it means everything
模块main是这个文件的名字
module main is the name of the file
它位于我们应用程序的根部
and it's at the root of our application
然后我们导入了三个不同的包
and then we are importing 3 different packages
浏览器
the browser
这样我们就可以实际创建一个应用程序
so that we can actually create an application
HTML，这样我们就可以渲染
HTML so that we can render
HTML
这一点很重要
it's kind of important
并导入HTML事件
and import HTML events
这样我们就可以在我们的应用程序中实际拥有事件
so that we can actually have events in our application
允许用户与页面进行交互
allow the user to interact with the page
然后我们初始化我们的状态，我们的模型为0
we then initialize our state our model to be 0
所以在这种情况下，我们的数据仅仅是一个数字
so in this case our data is just the number
我们不需要担心任何复杂的问题
we're not worrying about anything complex
而且它只是从数字0开始的
and it just starts out at the number 0
然后，我们有一个更新函数
we then have our update function
更新函数接收一个信息
the update function takes a message
在这种情况下，这个消息是一个联合体，它包括
in this case the message is a union of either
增量或减量
increment or decrement
然后
and then
我们的更新函数本身有一个类型签名
our update function itself has a type signature
其中它接收一个消息
where it takes a message
和一个模型，并返回一个模型
and a model and it returns a model
所以
so
在下一行我们可以看到更新消息模型
on the next line we can see update message model
我们现在有了这些变量，如果消息的增量是
we have those variables now case message of increment
模型加一
model plus one
所以我们正在增加我们的模型
so we're increasing our model
这是个数字加一
which is a number plus one
如果我们把模型-1减去
and if we decrement model -1
然后在我们的视图中
and then in our view
我们有一些HTML，我们正在渲染
we have some HTML that we are rendering
所以这就是渲染HTML的结构
so this is the structure for rendering HTML
如果我们想把它渲染成div
if we want to render it div
实际上是任何HTML元素
actually any HTML element really
我们有
we have
元素，即我们所说的
the element what we are calling
它本身就是一个函数，在本例中为div
which is itself a function div in this case
有
with
2个括号表示属性
2 brackets for the attributes
在这种情况下，这个div没有属性
in this case the div has no attributes
然后是第二个
and then a second
一组大括号，用于表示子节点的列表
set of brackets for a list of children
因此，这个 div 没有属性，但它有子代
so the div has no attributes but it does have children
一个按钮
a button
具有取消点击递减的属性
has attribute of unclick decrement
然后是一个文本减去的孩子
and then a child of the text minus
然后我们渲染另一个没有属性的 div
we then render another div with no attributes
和模型的文本
and the text of the model
所以我们要把这个数字
so we're turning the number
变成一个字符串，这样我们就可以把它渲染到用户界面上。
into a string so we can render it to the UI
然后我们有另一个按钮，用于递增
and then we have another button for incrementing
我们将在后面的代码示例中看到这一点。
and we are going to see this later in our code examples
我只是想让大家了解一下这个
I just wanted to walk through what this
榆树代码之前所做的
Elm code did before
我们到达那里
we got there
然后
and then
我们有一个主函数
we have our main function
主函数的作用是
the main function is what is
用来实际启动应用程序
used to actually initiate the application
向浏览器渲染一些东西
to render something to the browser
所以在这种情况下，我们使用的是浏览器沙盒
so in this case we are using browser sandbox
这只是意味着它
this just means it
不能与自身以外的javascript交流
can't communicate with javascript outside of itself
然后我们在它里面初始化，等于在它里面
and then we initialize in it equals in it
更新等同于更新，视图等同于视图
update equals update and view equals view
这看起来应该有些熟悉
this should look somewhat familiar
如果你习惯了javascript的对象符号
if you are used to javascript object notation
但我们用等号来代替冒号
but instead of colons we are using equal signs
这就是
and this is the
基本的Elm应用程序
basic Elm application
你可以从这里开始
you could start here
你可以开始扩展
you could start expanding
你可以开始探索如何编写Elm本身
you could start exploring how to write Elm itself
现在，我们只想看看
and right now we're just going to look
现在我们只想看看如何从小麦和Elm一起开始。
at how we can get started with wheat and Elm together
所以我们将进入一些代码
so we're going to go into some code
我有一个使用类型脚本的小麦启动器的例子
I have an example wheat starter using type script
我们将把Elm纳入该启动器中
and we're going to incorporate Elm into that starter
并将我们刚才看到的计数器渲染到
and render the counter that we were just looking at
到dom
to the dom
所以这是主TS文件
so this is the main TS file
报告一些样式
reporting some styles
报告typescript标识设置计数器
reporting the typescript logo setup counter
并生成了一些HTML
and generating some HTML
而我们只是要删除所有这些，在
and we are just going to delete all of this at
只需一秒钟
just one second
所以我们要做的第一件事是安装
so the first thing we're going to do is install
插件，以便在Wheat中使用Elm。
plug in for using Elm inside of wheat
所以我们要做mpm安装wheat
so we're going to do mpm install wheat
feat
plug in Elm，这将给我们提供一个插件
plug in Elm and that will give us the plug in
来在E中使用Elm
to use Elm inside of e
如果这是你第一次使用Elm
if this is the first time you've used Elm
你还需要做 npm install global
you'll also need to do npm install global
Elm，这将给你提供Elm编译器在
Elm that will give you the Elm compiler in
所有的语言
all of the language
中的所有语言编译器，你需要
pieces that you need
在你的全局范围内
in your global scope
我已经做了，所以我们不打算在这里做。
I've already done that so we're not going to do it here
我们需要做的下一件事是
the next thing we need to do is
启动我们的Elm邻近文件
initiate our Elm adjacent file
要做到这一点，我们只需在其中运行Elm
and to do that we just run Elm in it
然后我们说是
and we say yes
如果你以前从未使用过Elm
if you've never used Elm before
你应该检查一下那个链接
you should check out that link
就像它说的那样
just like it's saying
但Elm dot Jason
but Elm dot Jason
相当于一个软件包点Jason文件
is the equivalent of a package dot Jason files
它有我们的依赖性
it has our dependencies
和什么类型的
and what kinds
源，以及我们正在看的
sources we're looking at
我们正在编写什么样的代码
what kind of code we're writing
所以现在我们已经有了所有这些东西
so now that we have all that in place
我们要创建我们的VT配置
we're going to create our VT config
vtw fig TS 我们要从VT导入define config
vtw fig TS we're going to import define config from VT
中导入define config，同时我们也要把
and we're also going to import
plug in作为Elm
plug in as Elm
从V的plug in l
from v plug in l
然后我们导出
then we export
defaults define config
plugins l
现在我们已经将LM添加到我们的VT配置中了
and now we have added LM into our VT configuration
所以我们可以开始导入LM代码了
so we can start importing LM code
所以让我们创建一个新的文件main
so let's create a new file main
LM全部
LM all
LM模块以大写字母开头
LM modules start with a capital letter
所以大写的m代表main
so capital m for main
我们要把这个转入
and we're just going to dump this in
这是同一个计数器
this is the same counter
就是我们刚才看到的那个计数器
that we were looking at just a little bit ago
完成这些后
with that done
现在我们要做的就是删除所有的东西
all we need to do now is delete everything
总是最棒的部分
always the best part
我们将从maine.l导入Elm。
we're going to import Elm from maine.l
这样我们就有了我们的应用程序
that gives us our application
然后，我们要做的是： const app
and then we're going to do const app
等于m dot main
equals m dot main
文件的名称
which is the name of the file
中的文件名，我们需要传递给它一个节点
in it and we need to pass it a node
本例中的节点将是一个实际的dom节点
the node in this case is going to be an actual dom node
文档查询选择器
document queries selector
应用
app
这就是我们需要做的，以便获得标记。
and that is all we need to do in order to get l marking
所以让我们运行mpm run dev
so let's run mpm run dev
一切都很顺利地编译了，我们可以看到这里我们有
everything compiled happily and we can see here we have
我们的应用程序，它是如此令人兴奋，这是一个计数器
our application it's so exciting it's a counter
不过最酷的是
what's really cool though
是我们也有时间旅行调试器
is we also have the time traveling debugger
所以我们可以在我们的代码中回溯我们所做的每一步
so we can walk back in our code every step we made
并看到发生在我们模型上的所有变化
and see all of the changes that happen to our model
调试时
when debugging something
这是个很好的方法，可以看到正在发生的事情
this is a great way to see what's going on
你的应用程序的当前状态是什么
what the current state of your application is
而且你可以
and you can
开始推理你接下来需要做什么
start reasoning about what you need to do next
而且它只是内置在插件中
and it's just built into the plugin
所以你不需要担心在浏览器上安装
so you don't need to worry about installing
一个插件到你的浏览器
a plugin to your browser
它仅仅是
it's just part of
的一部分，而且你会带着它。
the v plugin out and that you're bringing with you
还有，当你查看调试器的时候
and also when you're viewing the debugger
Elm会暂停
Elm will pause
这样你就可以看到状态是什么
so that you can see what the state is
当你把它移到某个地方时
when you move it to a certain place
而当你点击恢复时
and when you click to resume
它就会移回它应该在的地方
it moves back to where it should be
在当前状态下
at the current state
很好，现在我们已经把Elm渲染到dom上了
great so now we have rendered Elm to the dom
使用v，但
using v but
我们不是从头开始
we're not starting from scratch
我们不是在写一个全新的应用程序
we're not writing a whole brand new application here
如果我们有一个现有的项目呢？
what if we have an existing project
如果你已经在视图中写了一个项目
what if you've been writing a project in view
写了好几个月甚至一年的项目
for some number of months or even a year
而且
and
你真的想试试Elm
you really want to try out Elm
但你不能把你已经写好的东西都扔掉
but you can't just throw everything out that you've
已经写好的东西
written already
你不需要担心
well you don't need to worry
因为Elm
because Elm
实际上可以并入任何一个前台
can actually be incorporated into any of the front
和框架
and frameworks
不管是view还是react
whether it's view or react
或Selt或Solid等等。
or selt or solid what have you
榆树
Elm
特别是通过小麦
especially through wheat
可以非常容易地被添加到任何这些框架中去
can be added very easily into any of these frameworks
这样你就可以尝试一下了
so that you can give it a try
所以这就是我们要做的事情
so that's what we're going to do
现在我们要深入研究视图启动器了
now we're going to dive into the view starter
使用npm创建视图
using npm create view
和
and
看看在我们的应用程序中添加Elm是什么感觉
see what it feels like to add Elm into our application
好的
all right
所以现在我们要像我说的那样看一下
so now we're going to look like I said at
视图3的默认模板
the view 3 default template
如果你以前从未看过它
and if you've never looked at it before
它是相当漂亮的，不是吗？
it's quite pretty isn't it
而我们要做的是
and what we're going to do is
就像我们之前做的那样
just like we did before
我们将在这个页面中加入Elm
we're going to be adding Elm into this page
但我们不是要替换掉所有的东西
but instead of replacing everything
我们只是要把它贴在这里的下面
we're just going to stick it here underneath
支持视图的地方
where it says support view
并让我们跳到代码中
and let's jump into the code
正如我们在上一个例子中所做的那样
as we did in our last example
第一步是安装mpm安装
the first step is to install mpm install
脚下的插件，如果你拼写正确的话，我
feet plug in if you spell it right l
和
and
我们已经安装了Elm，所以我们可以在其中运行Elm
we already have Elm installed so we can run Elm in it
我们可以让我们的Elm配置启动并运行
and we can get our Elm config up and running
因为我们使用的是视图模板
and because we're using the view template
我们已经有了一个v配置文件
we already have a v config file
我们已经在导入视图了
we are already importing view
所以我们只是要添加Elm，在这种情况下导入
so we're just going to add Elm in this case import
榆树
Elm
从
from
v plug and Elm
然后就在这里添加它
and then just add it right here
所以现在我们把view和Elm都作为插件了
so now we have both view and Elm as plugins
这就是我们需要做的，以使
and that's all we need to do in order to
这就是我们需要做的，以便让Elm启动和运行
have Elm up and running
所以现在
so now
我们要像之前那样创建
we're going to create just like we did before
我们将创建我们的主LM文件
we're going to create our main LM file
粘贴我们一直在使用的完全相同的代码
paste in the exact same code that we've been using
它是相同的计数器，渲染相同的HTML
it's the same counter rendering the same HTML
但这次不是替换所有的代码
but this time instead of replacing all of the code
我们将在视图中渲染这个内容
we're going to render this inside of view
所以让我们看看你需要做什么
so let's take a look at what you need to do that
在这个例子中
for this example
我们将把它插在欢迎页面中
we are going to be sticking it inside of the welcome
本例中的 "欢迎 "就在这里
the welcome in this case is right here
你可以看到我们在这里得到了文件
and you can see where we've got documentation
我们已经有了工具
we've got tooling
而我们只是要在底部添加一个
and we're just going to add one at the bottom
作为一个欢迎项目
as a welcome item
来
to
谈论函数式编程
talk about functional programming
所以我们就从这里开始
so we'll just start here
谈谈欢迎项目
with a welcome item
和
and
首先，我们将添加一个模板图标
first we'll add a templates icon
我们将在这里使用一个图标
and we're going to use an icon over here
像这样
like this
然后我们将添加模板
then we're going to add templates
标题
heading
功能性编程
functional programming
这就是我们的Elm要去的地方
and this is where our Elm is going to go
所以现在我们先放一个差值
so for now let's just put a diff
这就是我们要渲染Elm应用程序的地方
this is where we're going to render our Elm application
所以现在在我们的导入中
so now in our imports
我们将像以前一样导入我们的应用程序
we are going to import our application just like before
从这里导入Elm，在这里是
import Elm from in this case it's
级别提高
level up
仍然是LM，我们还将导入2个
remain LM we're also going to import 2
视图组合API的功能
of the view composition API features
我们将导入ref
we're going to import ref
并加载
and on mounted
现在，我们已经导入了这些
now that we've imported these
我们要做的第一件事是说 const Elm node
the first thing we're going to do is say const Elm node
等于 ref，我们不需要在那里放任何值
equals ref and we don't need to put any values there
我们将在一秒钟内使用它
we'll use it in just one second
然后我们将使用on mounted钩子
and then we're going to use the on mounted hook
on mounted 我们将使用 constap equals
on mounted we're going to sit constap equals
和我们之前做的一样，Elm dot main
same as we did before Elm dot main
中，但在这一次
in it but in this time
而不是使用一个文档查询选择器
instead of using a document query selector
我们只是说节点
we're just going to say node
榆树节点值
Elm node value
这样我们就可以访问该节点中的值了。
so that we can access the value inside of that
参考的
referential
对象内的值
object
这样就可以把我们的应用实例化了
and that will instantiate our app
除了Elm节点目前是空的
except Elm node is currently empty
所以在视图中，为了使用一个引用
so in view in order to use a ref
我们需要在dom元素本身上定义它
we need to define that on the dom element itself
dim div ref equals Elm node
这就是我们需要做的一切
and that's all we need to do
在这一点上，一切都应该按预期工作
at this point everything should be working as expected
和pm运行
and pm run
dev
如果我们跳回到这里
and if we jump back over here
我们看到了我们的 "d bugger"。
we see our d bugger
我们看到函数式编程，我们看到
we see functional programming and we see that
l maplication正在运行
the l maplication is running
好了，让我们回顾一下今天的内容吧
alright let's recap what we've looked at today
当你在使用Elm和V的时候
when you're using Elm and v together
你所拥有的
what you have
是一种函数式编程语言，你可以使用
is a functional programming language that you can use
在前端使用
in the front end
你不会被束缚在后端
you're not tied to the back end
你不需要担心数据模型和
you're not just worrying about data models and
抽象理论
abstract theories
你实际上是在写
you're actually getting to write
在浏览器中出现的代码
code that appears in the browser
这总是非常有趣的
which is always so much fun
你也有一个有用的编译器
you also have a helpful compiler
来指导你的重构工作
that is guiding you as your refactoring
在你学习的时候也是如此
as you're learning as well
而且你不必担心运行时的
and you're not having to worry about the runtime
在javascript中可能遇到的错误
errors that you can run into in javascript
不能读取未定义的空或
no cannot read null of undefined or
的任何
any of the
在javascript开发中出现的问题
issues that come up in javascript development
你不会遇到这些运行时问题
you're not going to run into those runtime issues
因为Elm只是
because Elm just
将它们全部避免了
avoids them all together
你还可以用小麦得到一个简单的配置，只需要
you also get a simple configuration with wheat with
一行代码
one line of code
你可以在任何基于小麦的应用程序中添加Elm
you can add Elm into any wheat based application
如果你想配置其他东西，也有一些选项
there are also options if you want to configure
插件来做其他事情
the plugin to do other things
但在默认情况下，你可能不需要它。
but by default you're probably not going to need that
有了这个，你可以把Elm添加到任何东西上
and with that you can add Elm to anything
你可以把它添加到标准V模板中
you can add it to a standard v template
你可以把它添加到视图启动器中
you can add it to the view starter
你可以把它添加到astro中
you can add it to astro
你可以把它添加到solid中 你可以把它添加到spelt中
you can add it to solid you can add it to spelt
无论你想要什么
whatever you want
榆树
Elm
你可以把Elm加到那里
you can add Elm there
并尝试一下，看看它的感觉如何
and try it out and see how it feels
这就是下一个好处
and that is the next benefit
与现有应用程序直接集成
straightforward integration with existing applications
你不必扔掉你的
you don't have to throw out your
你不必扔掉你已经存在的代码库
code base that already exists
而事实上，这是很
and in fact that's highly
强烈建议你不要这样做
it's highly recommended that you do not do that
如果你想尝试Elm
if you want to try out Elm
最好的方法是作为一个实验
the best way to do it is as an experiment
在一个现有的代码库和现有的应用程序中
in an existing code base and existing application
并专注于一个单一的功能
and focused on one single feature
这样你就可以在那一个地方感受到Elm的魅力了
that way you can get a feel for Elm in that one place
而如果你或
and if you or
如果你或你的团队认为这并不适合你
your team decides this isn't the fit for you
就很容易退缩或
it's really easy to either back out or
不仅仅是把它留在那里
not just leave it there
但这只是一个功能而已
but it's only that one feature
你不需要担心
you don't have to worry about
哦，我们重建了我们的整个单页应用程序
oh where we rebuilt our entire single page application
而现在我们被卡住了
and now we're stuck
你可以只把它
you can just keep it
在那一个地方，或者把它全部拿掉
in that one spot or take it out all together
以你的团队的喜好为准
whichever your team's preferences
因此，我有一个问题要问你
so with that I just have one question for you
你还在等什么？
what are you waiting for
我强烈建议你尝试使用velma
I highly recommend you give velma try
我很喜欢用它工作，我想你也会喜欢的。
I've loved working with it and I think you will too
我希望你喜欢这个讲座，希望你能学到很多东西。
I hope you enjoyed this talk hope you learned a lot
如果你想聊天，我随时都可以在网上
I'm always around online if you want to chat
和讨论这些事情
and discuss these kinds of things
你可以在Twitter上找到我：Lindsay K Wardell
you can find me on twitter at Lindsay k wardell
我也可以在 "午餐设计 "的 "Elm "聊天。
I'm also available to chat about Elm on the lunch dev
迪斯科服务器
discord server
希望能在这里见到你，祝你会议愉快
hope to see you around have a great conference